I spend most of my time
我生活中的大部分时间都在思考
thinking about little girls,
关于小女孩的事情，
which is kind of a weird thing for a grown man in our society to say.
这对于当今社会一位成年男性而言未免有些奇怪。
But I do. I spend most of my time thinking about little girls,
但是我确实花了大量时间在思考小女孩的事，
and I think it's primarily because I have one.
我想主要原因是因为我有一个女儿吧。
This one's mine, and I think you would really like her.
这是我的女儿，我想你们会喜欢她的。
She is smart and funny
她聪慧过人，活泼可爱，
and kind to people and a good friend.
待人友好，是个不错的小伙伴。
But when I talk about my daughter, the word I find myself saying most
但是当谈到我的女儿，我发现我说的最多的词是
is "athlete."
“运动员”。
My kid's athletic.
我的孩子身体素质很好。
She is strong and fast
她强壮，敏捷，
and has great balance and good body control.
有着很棒的平衡感和良好的身体协调性。
She is a three-time, back-to-back-to-back state champion in Shaolin Kempo.
她在持续三天的少林拳法比赛中，获得了三次州冠军。
At nine years old, she is already halfway to a black belt.
九岁的她已接近黑带水平。
My daughter is athletic.
我的女儿有着运动员的体魄。
Now, when a man who is six feet two and 265 pounds stands in front of you
现在，一个高1.86米。重120公斤的大汉站在你面前，
and says his daughter is athletic,
说她的女儿是运动员，
you might think that's a reflection of him.
你也许会想，应该是遗传他的吧。
It is not.
并不是这样的。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
My wife in high school was a two-time all-state soccer player
我的妻子在高中曾两次代表全州参加足球比赛，
and a two-time all-state volleyball player,
还两次代表全州参加排球比赛，
and I played "Dungeons and Dragons."
而我那会儿还玩着“龙与地下城”。
And that is why,
那也就是为什么，
although my daughter is an athlete,
我的女儿不仅仅是个运动员，
she's also a huge nerd, which I love.
她也是个技术能手，我很喜欢她这点。
She walks around our house in a cloak of flames
她身披火焰斗篷在家中穿行，
that she made herself.
这是她亲手制作的。
She sits on the Iron Throne --
她坐在铁王座上，（译注：来源于权力的游戏）
(Laughter)
（笑声）
even though she has never seen "Game of Thrones,"
即使她未曾看过《权利的游戏》，
primarily because we are not the worst parents who ever lived.
主要是因为我们并不是最糟的父母。
But she knows there's someone called the Mother of Dragons,
但她知道有人叫做龙母，
and she calls herself that and she loves it.
她也自称龙母并怡然自得。
She's a huge comic book fan.
她是个大大的漫画爱好者。
Right now, her favorite character is Groot.
现在，她最喜欢的角色是格鲁特。
She loves Groot.
她喜欢格鲁特。
She adores The Incredible Hulk.
她崇拜绿巨人浩克。
But my daughter really at heart,
但是在我女儿的内心中，
her thing is Star Wars.
星球大战才是她的最爱。
My kid is a Jedi.
我的孩子是个绝地武士。（星球大战中的重要组织）
Although some days she's also a Sith,
尽管有时她也扮成西斯，（绝地武士的宿敌）
which is a choice that I can respect.
是个令我敬佩的选择。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
But here's the question that I have to ask.
但是我一直有个困惑，
Why is it that when my daughter dresses up,
为什么当我的女儿想要换装打扮时，
whether it's Groot or The Incredible Hulk,
无论是格鲁特还是绿巨人，
whether it's Obi-Wan Kenobi or Darth Maul,
无论是欧比旺·克诺比，还是达斯·摩尔，（都是星球大战中的人物）
why is every character she dresses up as a boy?
为什么她饰演的都是男性角色？
And where are all the female superheroes?
女性超级英雄都去哪了？
And that is not actually the question,
这么问并不确切，
because there's plenty of female superheroes.
因为世界上有很多女性英雄。
My question really is, where is all the female superhero stuff?
事实上，我的问题是，所有女英雄的周边产品都哪儿去了？
Where are the costumes? Where are the toys?
她们的服装，形象玩具都在哪儿？
Because every day when my daughter plays when she dresses up,
因为当我的女儿每天换装扮演时，
she's learning stuff
她都在学习，
through a process that, in my own line of work,
在我自己的本职工作中，
as a professor of media studies,
作为一个媒体分析领域的教授，
we refer to as public pedagogy.
我们把这个过程称为公共教育学。
That is, it is how societies are taught ideologies.
也就是说，这关于社会如何被赋予意识形态。
It's how you learned what it meant to be a man or a woman,
它让你懂得，作为一名男性或女性的意义，
what it meant to behave yourself in public,
在公共场合自我表现的意义，
what it meant to be a patriot and have good manners.
成为一个忠心耿耿又彬彬有礼的人的意义。
It's all the constituent social relations that make us up as a people.
就是这些所有的社会关系组成了我们大家。
It's, in short, how we learn what we know about other people
简而言之，那就是我们如何了解到，我们对于其他人的认知，
and about the world.
以及我们对于全世界的认知。
But we live in a 100-percent media-saturated society.
但是我们生活在一个媒体无处不在的社会中。
What that means is that every single aspect of your human existence outside of your basic bodily functions
也就是说，人类在基本生理机能之外的每一个方面，
is in some way touched by media.
都多多少少与媒体有关联。
From the car that you drive to the food that you eat
从你开的车，吃的食物
to the clothes that you wear
到你穿的衣服，
to the way you construct your relationships
到你建立人际关系的方式，
to the very language you use to formulate thought --
到你表达思路时所使用的特有的语法——
all of that is in some way mediated.
所有这些都以某种方式被媒体化了。
So the answer in our society
所以，在我们的社会中，
to how do we learn what we know about other people and about the world
关于如何了解自己对于其他人和世界的认知，
is largely through media.
答案就是很大程度上，是通过媒体的。
Well, there's a wrinkle in that,
然而，有一个在媒体中存在，
in that our society,
在社会中也同样存在的小问题，
media don't simply exist as information distribution technologies and devices.
媒体并不单单作为信息发布的技术和设备而存在，
They also exist as corporate entities.
它们也作为企业的实体而存在。
And when the distribution of information is tied to financial gain,
并且，当信息的发布与商业利益挂钩时，
there's a problem.
就出现了问题。
How big of a problem?
多么严重的问题呢？
Well think about this:
试想一下：
in 1983, 90 percent of American media were owned by 50 companies.
在1983年，五十家公司掌控着全美国百分之九十的媒体。
In any market, 50 companies doing something is a lot of companies.
在任何市场领域，五十家公司共营意味着很多个公司。
It's a lot of different worldviews.
意味着许多不同的世界观。
In 2015, that number has shrunk to six,
在2015年，公司的数目锐减到了六个，
six companies.
六家公司。
They are NBCUniversal Comcast, AOL Time Warner,
它们是NBC环球集团，AOL时代华纳公司，
the Walt Disney Company, News Corp, Viacom and the CBS Corporation.
迪士尼公司，新闻集团，维亚康姆以及CBS公司。
These six companies produce nine out of every 10 movies you watch,
这六家公司制作了你所接触过的绝大多数电影，
nine out of every 10 television shows, nine out of every 10 songs,
绝大多数的电视节目，绝大多数的歌曲，
nine out of every 10 books.
绝大多数的书籍。
So my question to you is,
所以我要问你们的是，
if six companies control 90 percent of American media,
如果六家公司控制着全美国百分之九十的媒体，
how much influence do you think they have over what you're allowed to see every day?
你们认为，在观看什么节目的问题上，它们对你们产生了多大的影响？
Because in media studies,
因为在媒体学的研究中，
we spend a lot of time saying that media can't tell us what to think,
我们花费大量的时间说明媒体并不能告诉我们去想什么，
and they can't; they're terrible at that.
它们确实不能，而且做得很糟糕。
But that's not their job.
不过那不是它们分内的事情。
Media don't tell us what to think.
媒体并不告诉我们要去想什么，
Media tell us what to think about.
媒体告诉我们要去思考什么。
They control the conversation,
它们掌控着我们的谈话内容，
and in controlling the conversation,
即使是现在，
they don't have to get you to think what they want you to think.
它们不必让你想到 它们想要让你想的东西，
They'll just get you thinking about the things they want you to think about,
它们仅仅是让你思考他们想要让你思考的事情，
and more importantly, not thinking about things they don't want you to think about.
更重要的是，不去思考它们不想让你思考的事情。
They control the conversation.
它们掌控了谈话内容。
How does this work in practice?
这在我们的实际生活中是如何奏效的呢？
Let's just take one of those companies.
让我们找到这六家公司中的一家。
We'll do an easy one.
一家简单的。
Let's talk about the Walt Disney Company for a second.
让我们聊聊迪士尼公司。
The reason why I always pick the Walt Disney Company is this.
我总是选择迪士尼公司的原因是，
Is there a single person in this room who has never seen a Disney movie?
在座的观众中有从未看过迪士尼电影的人吗？
Look around. Exactly.
看吧，答案显而易见。
I picked Disney because they have what we call 100 percent penetration
我选择迪士尼公司是因为，用我们的话说，它百分之百的
in our society.
渗透进了我们的社会。
Every single person has been exposed to Disney,
每一个人都曾经接触迪士尼，
so it's an easy one for me to use.
所以我用它来举例效果最好。
Since 1937, Disney has made most of its money selling princesses to girls.
从1937年开始，迪士尼就通过向女孩儿们出售公主玩偶赚钱。
It's made a huge chunk of its money.
他们为此大赚了一笔。
Unless, of course, the princess your daughter is interested in,
当然，除非你的女儿和我的女儿一样，
as my daughter is, is this one.
喜欢这样的角色。
See, in 2012,
看看吧，在2012年，
Disney purchased LucasFilm for the sum of four billion dollars,
迪斯尼总共花了40亿美元收购卢卡斯影业，
and immediately they flooded the Disney stores with Han Solo
之后汉索罗，欧比旺・肯诺比，达斯·维德，
and Obi-Wan Kenobi, with Darth Vader and Luke Skywalker and Yoda
卢克·天行者和尤达（星球大战人物），就迅速占据了迪斯尼商店。
and not Princess Leia.
但却没有莱娅公主（同为星球大战人物）。
Why?
为什么？
Because this princess messes up the public pedagogy for these princesses.
因为这名公主会扰乱我们对这些公主的公共认知。
So Disney did not put Princess Leia merchandise in the store,
所以迪斯尼并没有把莱娅公主商品化。
and when people went to Disney and said,
当人们跑到迪斯尼并询问，
"Hey, where's all the Princess Leia stuff?"
“嘿，莱娅公主的商品在哪儿呢？”
Disney said, "We have no intention
迪斯尼回答：“我们并不打算
of putting Princess Leia merchandise in the store."
提供莱娅公主的周边商品。”
And fans were angry and they took to Twitter
所以粉丝们很生气，他们在Twitter上
with the hashtag #WeWantLeia.
发起了标签，＃我们想要莱娅。
And Disney said, "Wait, that's not what we meant.
然后迪斯尼回复，“等一下，那不是我们的本意。
What we meant was,
我们的意思是，
we don't have any Princess Leia merchandise yet, but we will."
我们目前还没有莱娅公主的相关商品，但我们会有的。”
And that was in 2012, and it is 2015,
那是在2012年的事了，到了2015年，
and if you go to the Disney Store, as I recently have,
如果你像我一样，最近去过迪斯尼商店，
and look for Princess Leia merchandise,
寻找莱娅公主的相关商品，
do you know how many Princess Leia items there are in the Disney Store?
你猜商店里有多少关于她的商品？
Zero, because Disney has no intention of putting Princess Leia in the store.
一件都没有，因为迪斯尼从来就不打算把莱娅公主放进商店。
And we shouldn't be surprised
我们不应该为此感到奇怪，
because we found out that was their policy when they bought Marvel in 2009 for the sum of 4.5 billion dollars.
因为那其实是他们在2009年，总共花了45亿美金收购漫威的时候就定好的政策。
Because when you make a lot of money selling princesses to girls,
因为之前通过向女孩们顷售公主玩偶赚了一大笔，
you also kind of want to make money from boys.
他们也想从男孩儿那挣点钱。
And so what better to sell boys than superheroes?
有什么比超级英雄更适合男孩们的吗？
So now Disney had access to Captain America and to Thor,
所以迪斯尼就有了美国队长，雷神，
The Incredible Hulk,
绿巨人，
and they had access even
他们甚至还拥有了一批
to a group of superheroes no one had ever even heard of.
我们没人听说过的超级英雄。
That's how good Marvel was at selling superheroes.
这体现了漫威是出色的英雄卖家。
Last year, they released a film called "Guardians of the Galaxy."
去年，他们发售了一部名叫《银河守护者》的影片。
It's a film that absolutely should not work.
这是一部绝不可能火的影片，
Nobody knew who they were except for comic book nerds like me.
因为除了像我这样的漫画书呆子，一般都没人听说过这些英雄。
One of the characters is a talking tree.
其中一个形象，是一棵会说话的树。
One of the characters is an anthropomorphic raccoon.
另一个形象则是一个拟人化的浣熊。
It should not work.
这怎么想也火不了啊。
And they made a killing off of "Guardians of the Galaxy."
但他们真的就拿着《银河守护者》大赚了一笔。
This character here in the middle, her name is Gamora.
这个中间的形象，她的名字是加美拉。
She's played by Zoe Saldana,
她是由佐伊·索尔达娜扮演的，
and she is strong and smart and fast and fights like a ninja,
她是一个坚强，聪颖，敏捷，打斗起来和忍者一样的形象，
and she is played by a beautiful black woman,
由一位美丽的黑人女性扮演，
and my daughter fell in love with her.
我的女儿爱上了这个形象。
So like any good nerd dad, I went to buy my daughter Gamora stuff,
所以，我就像一般的好爸爸那样，去给女儿买加美拉的周边商品。
and when I got to the store, I learned a very interesting thing.
当我到了商店，我得知了一件十分有趣的事情。
If I wanted to buy her a Gamora backpack,
如果我想给她买一个加美拉书包，
well, Gamora's not on it.
上面是没有加美拉的。
They probably should have marketed this as "some" of the Guardians of the Galaxy.
也许他们在打标牌的时候，应该标成《银河守护者》中的“某些人”。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
And if I wanted to buy her a lunchbox, she wasn't on it,
如果我想给她买个午饭袋，
and if I wanted to buy her a t-shirt, she wasn't on it.
加美拉也不在上面。T恤也是一样的。
And as a matter of fact,
事实上，
if I went to the store, as I did,
如果我去商店，我确实去看过了，
and looked at the display,
会看到在展品区，
you would find a small picture of Gamora right here,
有一个加美拉的小照片在这儿。
but if you look at any of the actual merchandise on that shelf,
但当你仔细看架子上的商品实物时，
Gamora is not on any of it.
你会发现加美拉没有出现在任何商品上。
Now, I could have taken to Twitter with the hashtag #WheresGamora,
现在，我可以在Twitter上发＃加美拉去哪儿了，
like millions of fans did across the world,
就像世界各地成千上万的粉丝们一样。
but the truth was I wasn't even really that surprised,
但事实上，我并不对此感到惊讶，
because I was there when Disney had released "The Avengers."
因为当迪斯尼播出《复仇者联盟》的时候我也经历过了。
And just this year, we got a new Avengers movie, the "Age of Ultron,"
就在今年，我们又迎来了复联的新续集《奥创纪元》，
and we were very excited,
然后我们很激动，
because there was not one but two female superheroes,
因为其中有，不是一个，而是两位女超级英雄，
Scarlet Witch and Black Widow.
腥红女巫和黑寡妇。
And we were very excited.
所以我们很激动。
But here's the real thing about this.
但真相是这样的。
Even though Scarlett Johansson,
即使是由斯嘉丽·约翰逊，
who is one of the most popular actresses in America, plays Black Widow,
美国当红女星扮演的黑寡妇；
and Black Widow is the star
即使黑寡妇形象存在于
of not one, not two, but five different Marvel movies,
不是一部两部，而是五部不同的漫威电影，
there is not a single piece of Black Widow merchandise available.
市场上也还是找不到任何关于黑寡妇的产品。
Not one.
一个也没有。
And if you go to the Disney store and look for a Black Widow costume,
如果你前往迪斯尼商店，寻找黑寡妇的服饰，
what you will find, is you will find Captain America and The Incredible Hulk.
你会发现，能找到的都是美国队长，绿巨人，
You will find Iron Man and Thor.
钢铁侠，或者雷神的服饰。
You will even find War Machine,
你甚至还能找到战争机器，（钢铁侠的好朋友）
who isn't even really in the movie that long.
在电影中都没怎么出镜的那种。
Who you will not find is Black Widow.
但是就是没有黑寡妇。
And I could have gone to Twitter with the hashtag, as many people did,
我本可以登录Twitter，像许多人那样贴个标签，
# WheresNatasha.
＃娜塔莎在哪儿。
But I'm tired of doing that.
但是我已经对这种行为感到疲惫了。
I'm tired of having to do that.
我对这种情况感到疲惫了。
All over the country right now,
现在全国上下，
there are kids playing with the Cycle Blast Quinjet play set,
孩子们都在玩一个基于复联专用战斗机场景的游戏，
where Captain America rides a motorcycle out of a moving jet
在其中，美国队长骑着摩托车冲出了飞行中的战斗机，
and it's really awesome.
那场面太酷了。
You know how awesome it is?
你能想象有多酷吗？
So awesome that when it happened in the movie,
在电影当中，也是这样的刺激，
it was Black Widow that did it.
这其实是黑寡妇的戏份。
Not only has she been erased,
不仅她的形象被抹去了，
but she has been replaced with a male figure.
还被一位男性形象所取代了。
And so what is this teaching us?
这又给了我们怎样的启示呢？
I mean, over the next five years,
我的意思是，在未来的五年当中，
Disney and Warner Bros. and a bunch of movie studios
迪士尼和华纳兄弟公司，还有一群电影工作室
are going to release over 30 feature-length films with comic book characters,
将会推出超过30部基于漫画形象的全长电影。
and of those 30 feature-length films,
在这超过30部电影中，
exactly two of them will have female solo leads.
准确来说只有两部将会由女性独立领导。
Two.
两部而已。
Now, there will be females in the rest of these movies,
虽然其他这些电影中也都是有女性形象的，
but they will be sidekicks, they will be love interests,
但她们都只是配角，爱情筹码，
they will be members of teams.
和团队中的一员而已。
They will not be the main character.
她们不会是主角。
And if what we learn, what we know
如果我们对其他人和
about other people and about the world we learn through media,
这个世界的认知都是通过媒体，
then these companies are teaching my daughter that even if she is strong
那么这些公司正在教育我的女儿，即使她很坚强，
and smart and fast and fights like a ninja,
很聪明，很敏捷，打斗起来像个忍者，
all four of which are true of her,
即使这些素质她都具备了，
it doesn't matter.
也毫无意义。
She will either be ignored like Gamora
她要不就会像加美拉那样被忽视，
or erased and replaced with a boy like Black Widow.
要不就会像黑寡妇那样，被其他男孩儿取代。
And it's not fair.
这不公平。
It's not fair to her and it's not fair to your sons and daughters either.
这对她不公平，对你们的儿子女儿们也不公平。
But here's the thing:
但关键在于：
I'm raising a little girl, and she has a little tomboy in her,
我正在养育一个小女孩儿，她的个性有点儿像假小子，
which by the way is a terrible thing to call a girl.
虽然听上去对一个女孩有点像贬义词，
What that basically is saying is, those traits that define you,
但是这些媒体传达给大众的却是，这些定义你们的东西，
they're not really yours,
并非属于你们，
they're just on loan to you for a little while from boys.
这些特质只是从男孩那儿暂时接过来的。
But do you know how much grief she's going to take in her life for having a little tomboy in her?
但是你知道她会因为假小子的性格而感到人生有多么令人悲伤吗？
Zero. None.
一点儿都不会。
People will think it's cute.
人们会认为这很可爱。
They'll call her feisty, because in our society,
人们会用争强好胜形容她，因为在这个社会当中，
adding so-called male traits to girls
女性具有一点儿所谓的男性特质，
is seen as an upgrade, seen as a bonus.
其实是一种升级，被认为是额外的优势。
I'm not raising a little boy, like Mike.
我没有抚养过像Mike这样的小男孩儿。
Mike is a little boy in Florida. He's 11 years old,
Mike是弗罗里达州的一名小男孩儿，他今年11岁。
and the thing that he loves most in the world
他在这个世界上最喜欢的东西，
is a show called "My Little Pony: Friendship is Magic,"
和美国其他成千上万的孩子们一样，
like millions of other children across America.
是一部动画片，名叫《小马驹之友谊魔法》。
Now, the show is marketed to girls ages five to nine,
这个动画的消费人群针对5-9岁的小女孩，
but there are millions of boys
但是却有不计其数的小男孩儿，
and grown men
还有成年男性
who enjoy "My Little Pony: Friendship is Magic."
也喜欢《小马驹之友谊魔法》。
They have a club.
他们成立了一个俱乐部。
They call themselves Bronies,
他们称自己为小马兄弟，
pony bros, guys who like ponies.
一群喜欢小马驹的男人。
I happen to be one of them.
我碰巧就是其中之一。
And what are Mike and myself
Mike和我，还有无数的
and millions of other boys and men learning in this feminine,
男孩和男人们，从这个女性化的
sissified world of "My Little Pony?"
“我的小马世界”里学到了什么呢？
Well, they're learning to study hard and to work hard and to party hard
他们懂得了努力学习，努力工作，努力玩耍，
and to look good and to feel good
懂得了举止得体，乐观自信，
and to do good,
行善积德，
and heaven preserve us from teaching these wussified concepts to boys.
而男孩生来就被避免了接触这些死板的概念。
So the other kids in his neighborhood pick on Mike and they beat him up
所以邻里的孩子就在Mike身上找茬儿，
and they make fun of him,
殴打他，嘲笑他，
and at 11 years old, Mike goes home,
作为一名11岁的男孩，Mike回到家，
finds a belt, wraps it around his neck,
找到了跟带子，套过脖子，
and hangs himself from the top bunk of his bed.
把自己挂在了上铺的床沿上。
Because we have developed a society
因为我们的社会决定了一种模式，
in which you would rather be dead as a boy than thought of as liking stuff for girls.
宁可做一名死去的男孩，也不愿被人说喜欢女孩的东西。
And that is not Mike's fault. That is our fault.
那不是Mike的错。那是我们的错。
We have failed him.
我们令他失望了。
We have failed our children.
我们令我们的孩子们失望了。
And we have to do better for them.
我们应该为了他们做得更好。
We have to stop making it so that the only female superheroes
我们必须停止这么做，不能让女超人的形象
appear on shirts that are pink and cut for girls.
只出现在针对女孩儿的，可爱的粉嘟嘟的T恤上。
We have to stop.
我们必须停止。
And when I was putting this together, people said to me,
当我这么说的时候，一些人回复我说：
"Well, that's never going to happen." And I said, "Oh really?"
“好吧，但那绝不可能发生。” 然后我说：“是吗？”
Because just this year, Target announced
因为就在今年，塔吉特（Target百货公司）宣布，
that they were going to stop gendering their toy aisles.
他们将要取消玩具的性别通道。
They were going to mix it up.
他们要把玩具混在一起。
Now, before we break our shoulders patting Target on the back,
不过，在我们准备支持塔吉特的时候，
just this week they released a shirt
他们在这周又发行了一款T恤，
in which one of the most iconic scenes in "Star Wars: A New Hope"
在上面印着“星球大战：曙光乍现”中最具标志性的一幕：
where Princess Leia stands up to the Dark Lord of the Sith,
莱娅公主直面西斯黑暗尊主。
was released on a t-shirt
但T恤上的画面，
in which she's mysteriously replaced by Luke.
莱娅却神秘的被卢克取代了。
So let's don't pat ourselves on the back too much.
所以我们也不能高兴得太早。
Just this week also,
同样是这周，
Disney announced it was no longer going to gender its Halloween costumes,
迪斯尼宣布他们不会再把万圣节服饰性别化了。
which I say, "Thank you, Disney,
我要说：“谢谢你，迪斯尼，
except the only costumes you make are of male superheroes,
你们的服饰本来就只印男性超级英雄，
so does it matter who you have wearing them?"
所以谁穿也没什么区别吧？”
Just this week, Mattel, who makes Barbie,
就在这周，生产了芭比娃娃的美泰公司，
announced they're going to release a line of DC superhero girls.
宣布他们将会发布超能英雄少女组合。
And the funny thing is,
有趣的是，
they met with girls
当他们和女孩儿们交流，
and asked them what they wanted to see in dolls,
询问她们想要怎样的娃娃时，
and you can see, they have calves
你会发现，她们想要那种
and elbows that bend so they can do superhero stuff.
手臂和腿部可以弯曲的，那样就可以作一些超人动作。
And please buy them.
请购买它们吧。
And don't just buy them for your daughters,
不要只买给你们的女儿们，
buy them for your sons.
也买给儿子们吧。
Because it's important that boys play with and as female superheroes
因为男孩们玩儿女版超人玩具，
just as my daughter plays with and as male superheroes.
就和我女儿玩男版一样意义重大。
As a matter of fact, what I would love
事实上，在我理想中的社会，
is a world in which every person who goes to the store
当每个人前往商店时，
goes with a little flowchart in their head
他们的脑海中只需要闪过一个小的流程图，
of whether or not they should buy this toy for a boy or a girl,
就能决定是否给男孩儿或是女孩儿买这种玩具，
and it's a real simple flowchart because it only has one question on it.
真的是很简单的流程图，因为其中只有一个问题：
It says, "Is this toy operated with your genitals?"
那就是：“这个玩具需要用到性器官吗？”
(Laughter)
（笑声）
If the answer is yes,
如果答案是肯定的，
then that is not a toy for children.
那这个玩具绝对少儿不宜！
(Laughter)
（笑声）
And if the answer is no,
如果答案是否认的，
then it's for boys and girls.
那这个玩具就同样适合男孩和女孩。
It's really simple.
就是这么简单。
Because today is about the future of the future, and in my future,
因为今天就决定了明天的明天，在我的明天中，
boys and girls are equally respected,
男孩和女孩是平等的，
equally valued, and most importantly, equally represented.
他们平等的被尊重，被重视，最重要的是平等的被象征。
Thank you.
谢谢。
(Applause)
（掌声）